

ABOUT ME

Have around 9+ years of experience as a Senior Software Engineer with experience in the field of software design, development & maintenance of web based applications, developed on J2EE platform with Oracle and Mssql as the back end database.

Has been extensively working on JAVA, J2EE, Spring framework, Spring boot, Spring cloud, Lombok, Reactive Spring, Webflux, JPA, Hibernate, Thymeleaf, HTML, Jersey (REST API), Oracle DB, Mssql, Maven, Sonarqube, Microservices etc. as the technological base.

Other responsibilities includes

- Adhering to agile methodology (Scrum) using Atlassian tools, have group discussions.
- Attend daily scrums standup meetings with Team. Interact with QA team and UI team.
- Attend trainings, Technical seminars.
- Coordinate with project team, Supervise/lead as well as exchange knowledge

Expertise:

- Web Technologies: Servlet, JSP, JSTL, JNDI, JMS, Web Service (REST), Jersey. JAX-RS, JAX-WS.
- Others: S.O.L.I.D design principles, Design patterns, OWASP security.
- Web Framework : Spring 5.x, JSF 2.x, Springboot 2.x

IMDAD AREEPH SENIOR SOFTWARE ENGINEER



Dubai, Dubai, United Arab Emirates



+971-507605159



imdadareeph@gmail.com

WORK EXPERIENCE

EMIRATES AIRLINES

Dubai, UAE Aug 2018 - Present

Senior Software Engineer

Responsible for:

- 1. Writing RESTful services, creating/modifying SOAP endpoints.
- 2. Manage code dependencies. Git code commit, CI/CD builds.
- 3. Writing JUnit Test cases with jacoco Code coverage.
- 4. Complete revamp of old feature in Microservice architecture
- 5. Leading the team for a Skywards Miles delivery

Project Name: Emirates Internet Booking Engine
Emirates Internet Booking Engine is the online portal that
manages the booking of flights along with various add-on
features. It facilitates the user to search for flight, select seat and
create E-Ticket using a rich UI experience and provides various
benefits as well as information.

EMIRATES NBD

Dubai, UAE Jun 2016 - Jul 2018

Consultant

Responsible for:

- 1. Code server side logic, Writing Restful services
- 2. Design the flow . Code review, documentation of user stories.
- 3. Module handling Insights/loans/RuleEngine/RM
- 4. Implement i18n for Arabic version and video banking feature.
- 5. Handle request/response from tibco /finacle /CRM /finOne.

Project Name: Facelift (Online Banking)

ENBD Banknet is the revamped version of an existing banking system with latest technologies with added features like video banking including core banking system. Video banking module included, gives the user to access banking features by connecting with agents via audio/video/chat features along with document uploads, Loan apply, etc.

MASTERCARD

Vadodara, IN Jan 2016 - May 2016

Software Engineer

Responsible for:

- 1. Follow Agile methodology using Rally
- 2. Involved in Core product development Server side coding.
- 3. Create Restfull services. Write business logic(Services)
- 4. Involved in execution of queries using sql developer.
- 5. Use atlassian products like Confluence,Bamboo, Bitbucket, Also Flowdock, Rally, Code coverage(SonarQuebe) etc

Project Name: MassterPass (Payment Wallet)

Masterpass is a digital wallet that simplifies the checkout process across your purchases online, in-app, and in-store with one secure account. No long checkout forms, forgotten passwords, or fumbling for a wallet. Just create your account and load any participating credit or debit card to get started.

Knowledge on:

- Third party frameworks:
 Primefaces 5.0/ 3.4, Spring
 Webflux, Microservies Zuul,
 Eureka, Hystrix
- Performance tool: JConsole, JvisualVM, Eclipse Memory Analyzer, JProfiler
- Servers: Tomcat 7, JBOSS EAP 6.2, Weblogic, Netty, Jetty, Payara
- IDE's: IntelliJ Idea, Spring Tool Suit, Eclipse.
- Build Tools/ CI/CD: Maven, Jenkins
- Versioning tool : Git , Sourcetree, SVN, TFS
- Code Review tool : Sonarqube-5.0.1,JaCoCo
- Project tool (For SCRUM):
 Confluence, Rally, Bitbucket,
 Jira

LANGUAGES

ENGLISH

ASSAMESE

HINDI

GERMAN

KOREAN

RUSSIAN

REFERENCES

RAHEEL KHAN

Mashreq Bank

T: +971 52 804 1144 **E:** raheelahmed.khan@dnata.com

MOHD FAIZ KHAN

Emirates Airlines

T: +971 55 180 3065 **E:** mohdfaizcs059@gmail.com

CAPGEMINI

Bangalore, IN May 2014 - Jan 2016

Senior Software Engineer

Responsible for:

- 1. Writing Backing Beans, Domain Classes, Service Classes.
- 2. Designed JSFs as per the requirements.
- 3. Integrated JSF, Spring, Hibernate, Primefaces, Webservices
- 4. Used Design Pattern like Strategy ,Facade ,MVC, Proxy etc.
- 5. R&D on VMware fusion on MAC OSX, VMware Workstation, Virtual Box on windows.

Project Name: LITE (Virtualization:: VNC)

LITE is a web based testing tool, to test web applications / web sites, to check compatibility across different browsers, on different versions and across different operating systems.

SWIZCOM

Bangalore, IN May 2013 - Apr 2014

Senior Software Engineer

Responsible for:

- 1. Writing Backing Beans Classes, Navigation Rules.
- 2. Designed JSFs as per the requirements.
- 3. Responsible for writing Domain Classes, Service Classes.
- 4. Writing HQL, Hibernate and Spring classes.
- 5. Do R&D on Memory Management, Spring Security, JMS

Project Name: nameMediSwiz (HMS)

MediSwiz HMS is a comprehensive and integrated Hospital Management System developed to cater to the needs of poly clinics to multi-specialty Hospitals.

ICT HEALTH

Bangalore, IN Dec 2011 - Apr 2013

Software Engineer

Responsible for:

- 1. Writing Backing Beans Classes, Navigation Rules.
- 2 Designed JSFs as per the requirements.
- 3. Responsible for writing Domain Classes, Service Classes.
- 4. Writing HQL, Hibernate and Spring classes.
- 5. Involve in Database as a backend and writing scripts.

Project Name: Hinai Web (HMS)

Hinai is a HIS solution, providing web based healthcare services and solution. This Hospital Information Systems application is completely deployed on cloud.ICTHEALTH has tied up with Many renowned hospitals to launch a hospital information system that will store patient records and other hospital data on cloud infrastructure.

COURSES

NIIT

Jun 2011 - Nov 2011

NIIT

Jun 2011 - Nov 2011

NIIT

Jun 2011 - Nov 2011

Advance Java and web Frameworks

Unix and Shell Scripting

Database learning

SKILLS

JAVA

SPRING

HIBERNATE

JPA

AWS

DOCKER

SHELL SCRIPTING

DATABASE

MICROSERVICE ARCHITECTURE

OPENSHIFT

GIT

MAVEN

JIRA

ICT

APPLICATION SERVERS

MESSAGE BROKER

PERSONAL DETAILS

Date of birth 3rd October

Nationality Indian

Visa statusUAE Residence Permit

Marital status Single

OTHERS

I Am A Blogger, Technologist, Internet Crazy; In Short, A Typical Software Engineer Who Falls In Love With Everything That Relates To Increase Knowledge And Create Innovations.

EDUCATION

BIT

Bangalore, IN 2011

Bachelor of Technology

Completed Bachelor of Engineering degree from VTU University, Karnataka, India.

COTTON COLLEGE

Guwahati, IN 2004

Associate of Science

Completed the 10+2 education with 65% marks in Physics Chemistry and Mathematics in Science stream

DON BOSCO

Guwahati, IN 2002

High school diploma

Completed the high school education from this school with 82.4% marks.

LINKS

Professional Profile:

http://imdadareeph.com/

Facebook:

https://facebook.com/imdadareeph

LinkedIn:

http://linkedin.com/in/imdadareeph/

Github:

https://github.com/imdadareeph

PUBLICATIONS

JWT OAUTH2 WITH KEYCLOAK

Aug 2020

KPI MANAGEMENT SPRINGBOOT

Jul 2020

AWS SQS SPRINGBOOT

Jun 2020

WEB APPLICATION

Dec 2016

SSO AND CAS

Aug 2015

JAVA WEB APPLICATION

Jan 2013

JWT oAuth2 with Keycloak Springboot

Springboot KPI Management Apllication

AWS SQS springboot implementation

Application Deployment on cloud

Single Sign On

Spring hibernate

HOBBIES

GUITAR PLAYING, PHOTOGRAPHY, SOCCER PLAYER, GAMING, HIKING, YOUTUBER, BLOGGING, TECHNICAL WRITER, DIARY WRITER, MUSIC & SONG WRITER.